hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation playlist now
continuing with our topic on the
automation obstacles so let's look at
our next obstacle which is related to
XML and how we can find something in XML
and also how we can enter that into a
particular text box right so this
particular obstacle is quite complex uh
because we have to use a number of
different engines okay so here we need
to click on this load books and then uh
XML structure will be loaded into this
particular text area Okay so uh you can
see this is currently disabled right so
we cannot directly search from here and
then we need need to also enter the
ISBN of a particular book name which is
testing computer software right so we
need to search through the XML find the
ISBN uh which title is this and then we
need to enter that into the text box now
in order to uh resolve this particular
obstacle we need to use couple of
engines like we need to use the browser
engine in order to click on the button
or in order to buffer the text uh which
is present here and then uh also in
order to enter it into the text box we
also need to use the file engine so that
we can create a new XML file and then we
need we can enter the text in present
here into that particular XML file we
also need to scan the XML file and also
we need to then use the XML engine to
basically find the ispn with this
particular book title okay so as you can
see there are lots of moving parts in
this particular obstacle and it's a very
good uh way of practicing what you have
learned until now in
tosa so let's go ahead and let's try to
resolve this particular obstacle or
let's try to um automate this particular
obstacle using
tosa okay so coming back to our tosa
workspace um let's go to our module
section and here uh we will go to the
obstacles and then uh I'm going to scan
this particular application
here okay before that uh I will just uh
refresh this page so that we are back to
the original state of this page and then
I'm going to scan this page okay so
initially uh we just require the Load
Books link okay and then we require uh
the text area and then we require the
text field where we need to enter the
Isn okay so these are the three controls
which we require uh and then uh we can
save this and we can close this okay uh
I'm going to copy this particular
obstacle ID so that I can uh rename this
module name as per
this okay uh this time around I'm also
going to create a folder okay uh now I'm
going to tell you why I'm doing this
later on but for now we are going to
create this folder and we are going to
place it this module inside this
particular folder okay okay so I'm I'm
going to rename this to load XML
right and uh we are going to put this
the obstacle number
right right uh and then uh we are going
to go to a test cases section here again
uh we will go to our obstacles where we
have been creating all the test cases we
are going to create our next next
obstacle test case uh again we are going
to use the same obstacle number okay and
then uh we are simply going
to uh put this module right here okay
and then um the first thing which we
need to do here is obviously to load the
XML right so we need to click on this
particular link and then uh the XML text
will be loaded in this particular box
text area okay and what we will do is we
will basically buffer this particular
text okay so we will store it into a
particular um buffer name so I'm going
to call this buffer XML
text after this right uh we need to
create a particular file and then we
need to uh write this particular text
into that file okay so now uh we are
going to search for a test step uh which
is called
create uh so tbox read create file right
so this is uh the module which I want
and here uh we are going to write it
into a particular directory
right so I'm going to write it into this
particular
directory
okay and uh the file name will be books.
XML and the text uh will be the buffer
okay so I'm going to use the buffer
which I have created earlier so I'm
going to call it XML
text okay and then in override I'm going
to set it to True okay so what this will
do is it will basically write the
content of this particular text which
has been generated and it will write it
into a file called box. XML okay
so I'm going to say write XML file so
this is the test
step so now uh we are going to first of
all execute this so that we can see that
XML file is created with that particular
text and then uh we need to scan that
particular XML file okay so let's go
ahead and execute these two steps for
now
okay so as you can see it clicked on the
load books and then the text was
generated uh it buffered the text and
then it created a file and then uh it
wrote the text into that particular file
okay uh if I go to that location you
will see the books. XML file is present
here although I had that file already
already it will also overwrite the text
if that particular file is already
present okay so if now I open this you
will see that it has got the particular
text which was generated okay and uh we
are looking for a particular title right
so we are looking for this particular
title and we want the ISBN which is like
an ID so we want this number and then we
need to enter this number into the text
box okay so these are the uh remaining
things which we need to do now in order
to do this right uh there are couple of
ways to do this but I'm going to follow
a different approach here so what I'm
going to do is I'm going to scan uh the
XML file and that can be done using the
scan option you should go to more and
here you will find a file scan option
okay now if I go to file scan I can
directly um browse any particular file
in this case it is an XML file so I'm
going to browse this okay and it is
going to create a module for this
particular file right so I am going to
call this books
XML okay and you will see it contains uh
resource and then it contains the uh all
the nodes for that particular XML file
okay now uh what we can do is we can go
back to our test case and then we can
add our third test step which is uh this
particular module right and here uh I'm
going to say
search book
title now before this we need to add
another step which is to open the XML
file because until now we haven't
actually open the XML file right so
let's go ahead and let's search for and
ADD test step and this time it will be
open
XML okay so this
one and then um I'm going to drag this
uh and put it before the search book
title so this is going to open uh the
XML file we need to provide it a
resource I'm going to call it uh books
and then uh the file path which will be
this
okay after this uh we will write books.
XML so this is going to open the XML
file I'm going to rename this to reflect
that particular test step and then we
are going to search for the book title
right again the resource uh should be
same whatever you are opening uh for the
XML file whatever resource you passed
the same name should be passed here so
the reference is passed here and then um
in the
catalog we can search for that
particular title okay so what is the
title is this testing computer software
right so I'm going to copy this
particular title here and I'm going to
paste it
here okay so instead of verify uh we are
going to put it as a
constraint okay now this uh constraint
what it will do it will search for this
particular type and then it will filter
it out right so that that particular um
node will be filtered out from the rest
of the XML right and after that uh what
we can do we can buffer the respective
ispn for this particular book title okay
now I'm going to give it above a name so
I'm going to call it bore
ISBN so now this uh will be basically
Search the book title and then grab the
ispn and store it in a buffer now the
last step which uh is pending is to just
write it into the text box so write our
result into the text box right so we are
going to again use the same module here
uh I'm going to rename this so we are
going to say enter
ispn okay and here we are just going to
use this particular text box okay so
here we'll be entering buffer
bore
ispn okay so this is what we are going
to
input so now uh the complete test case
is completed so I'll change the work
state to completed here so as you can
see there are lots of different steps
here right so first uh we clicked on the
link We generated the XML text then uh
we wrote that text into a particular
file and then we opened that particular
XML file then uh we read the XML file
and we searched for the title we got the
ispn we buffered the ispn and finally we
entered the ispn uh in in the input text
box right so now this is completed now
let's go ahead and U run this again okay
so I'm going to refresh this page this
time around we are going to run the
complete steps so let's go ahead and run
this okay so as you can see uh it has
entered the particular ispn for that
particular book title now if you want to
verify that you can easily do that go to
your books XML and you can see the
particular
ispn so this is how you can resolve this
complex automation problem
uh we have to use different engines like
the XML engine and the browser engine
then we need to use different standard
modules like we have to use uh the
create file standard module we have to
use the open XML file module uh we have
to use a buffer at similar places to
buffer the values so we have to use a
lot of different things uh in this
particular automation problem and it's a
good test as I said earlier of your uh
tosa skills in order to automate this
particular
problem that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next video